Saptarshi Chatterjee

Email: saptarshichatterjee1@gmail.com Phone: +1 773-313-5008

Summary

Enterprise Web Application Architect. Full Stack Engineer with expertise in web security, performance, Java, Spring Boot, Design Patterns, Kafka, HDFS, HBase, Hive, Spark and Hadoop. Author, speaker, Blogger, and a geek. 8+ Years of experience in FullStack Web Technologies (Spring Boot, React, Redux, Webpack, nodeJs, Java, Mysql, Cloud Computing)

Experience



Engineering Manager

Aug 2017 - Dec 2017

HomeAway

I was responsible for creating Customer Experience Progressive WebApp using Spring Boot in the Backend and React, Redux in the front end.

Responsible for development and maintenance of Kafka Cluster to hold Click Streams . Created Spark Streaming Application to find the most clicked part of the landing page.

Paytm

Engineering Manager

Apr 2016 - Aug 2017

Paytm

A fullstack web developer. My main responsibility is to spearhead maintenance and revamp of Paytm Desktop and Mobile Websites . Core competencies are Spring Boot, NodeJs, Kafka, express, nginx , Isomorphic React , webpack , HML5, CSS3 , AWS.



Technical Lead

Feb 2014 - Apr 2016

McKinsey & Company

Created business solutions for Multiple Fortune 500 clients across Asia Pacific . Mainly worked with Spring Boot, NodeJs, React , Redux and WebPack



Software Engineer

Aug 2012 - Feb 2014

Worked as a Software Engineer for SlideShare. Was responsible for Creating JavaScriptSlideshow viewer, Dynamic Sitemap generator and LinkedIn integration. Worked with Ruby onRails, Mysql and JavaScript.



Program analyst

Sep 2009 - Feb 2012

Cognizant

LinkedIn

Worked for 2.5 years in Cognizant, Kolkata as Programmer Analyst in Banking and FinancialSystem verticals. Key responsibilities were writing predictive algorithms in Java to Select theBest Suited financial products for Client.

Education



Illinois Institute of Technology

2018 - 2020

Artificial Intelligence, 3.66



Madhyamik Examination (Hare School)

10th grade, General Studies, 85.6



West Bengal Council Of Higher Secondary Education (Hare School)

Higher Secondary, Science, 91.3



West Bengal University of Technology

B.Tech, Computer Science And Engineering, 75

NETAJI SUBHASH ENGG. COLLEGE

Skills



Spring Framework • Node.js • Apache Kafka • Apache Spark • Hadoop • HDFS • HBase • Java • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • React.js

Honors & Awards

LinkedIn HackDay 2013 • LinkedIn • Oct 2013

Worthy Mention, LinkedIn/SlideShare Hack Day(http://engineering.slideshare.net/2013/10/brilliant-hacks-at-slideshare-hackday-2013/)

HikeAthon 2014 • Hike • Dec 2014

The Biggest Online Coding Challenge .HikeAthon . 3rd Runner Up . http://hikeathon.hackerrank.com. Team 20PercentHike

Npm Author • https://www.npmjs.com • Mar 2014

Authored AngularJS test generator npm module. It's a yeoman generator. Generates customized Jasmine test for your angularJs file.

https://www.npmjs.com/package/generator-yosapy

Winner, MDL India Hackathon, 2015 • Mckinsey Digital Lab • May 2015

1st Prize (iPAD mini for all the team members)

Team - SWAT Kats.